A Guide to the William A. Pence general store records, 1859-1907
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
William A. Pence general store records, 1859-1907
The Library of Virginia
28039
48 volumes and 1 box
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased May 1973.
Biographical Information
William Anderson Pence was born on 8 April 1838 in Shenandoah County, Virginia, to Lewis and Rebecca Pence. He owned a general store in Timberville, Rockingham County, Virginia, and married Mary H. Wunder (1843-1922) in 1866. During the Civil War he served with the 7th Virginia Cavalry, Company K. He was injured at the Battle of Haws Shop in Hanover County and was a prisoner of war at Ft. Delaware, Delaware. He died in 1922 and was buried at Mt. Jackson Cemetery, Shenandoah County, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Records, 1859-1907, of William A. Pence's general store in Timberville, Rockingham County, Virginia. Includes accounts, cashbooks, correspondence, daybooks, and ledgers. Information found in the records includes date of transaction, name of customer, items purchased, quantity of items purchased, amount owed, and amount paid. Items sold include dry-goods, groceries, tobacco, whiskey, hardware, tinware, boots, and cloth.
Contents List
- Advertisements, accounts, and correspondence, 1860-1903. (Box 1)
- Accounts with food wholesalers, 1899-1907. (Volume on shelf)
- Cash books, 1885-1894. (Volume on shelf)
- Cash books, 1902-1904. (Volume on shelf)
- Cash books, 1904-1906. (Volume on shelf)
- Cash book, 1906-1907. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1860-1861. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1875. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1875-1876. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1876-1877. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1877. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1877-1878. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1878-1879. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1879. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1879-1880. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1883-1884. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1884-1885. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1885-1886. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1886-1887. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1887-1888. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1888-1889. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1889-1890. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1890-1891. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1891-1892. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1892-1893. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1893-1894. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1894. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1894-1895. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1895-1896. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1896-1897. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1897-1898. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1898-1900. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1900-1901. (Volume on shelf)
- Day book, 1903-1904. (Box 1)
- Day book, 1904-1905. (Box 1)
- Day book, 1905. (Box 1)
- Day book, 1905-1906. (Box 1)
- Day book, 1906-1907. (Box 1)
- Ledger, 1859-1872. (Volume on shelf)
- Ledger, 1866-1871. (Volume on shelf)
- Ledger, 1869-1871. (Volume on shelf)
- Ledger, 1875-1878. (Volume on shelf)
- Ledger, 1876-1879. (Volume on shelf)
- Ledger, 1879-1883. (Volume on shelf)
- Ledger, 1883-1887. (Volume on shelf)
- Ledger, 1887-1893. (Volume on shelf)
- Ledger, 1893-1896. (Volume on shelf)